<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>50-1301.37</num>
  <heading proof="needed">Suspension of license and registration upon conviction of certain offenses; exceptions; transmission of judgments.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The DMV shall suspend, in accordance with the requirements of <cite path="§50-1301.38">§ 50-1301.38</cite>, the license and registration of any person who was convicted or adjudicated a juvenile delinquent by a final order or judgment for, or who forfeited any bond or collateral given to secure their appearance for trial for a violation of, the following offenses:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Driving under the influence (DUI) of alcohol or a drug, as described in <cite path="§50-2206.11">§ 50-2206.11</cite>;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Driving under the influence of alcohol or a drug; commercial vehicle, as described in <cite path="§50-2206.12">§ 50-2206.12</cite>;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Operating a vehicle while impaired, as described in <cite path="§50-2206.14">§ 50-2206.14</cite>;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Any homicide resulting from a person being struck by a motor vehicle, including:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Murder in the first degree, as described in <cite path="§22-2101">§ 22-2101</cite>;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Murder in the second degree, as described in <cite path="§22-2103">§ 22-2103</cite>;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Manslaughter; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Negligent homicide, as described in <cite path="§50-2203.01">§ 50-2203.01</cite>;</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Leaving after colliding, as described in <cite path="§50-2201.05c">§ 50-2201.05c</cite>;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Aggravated reckless driving, as described in <cite path="§50-2201.04|(b-1)">§50-2201.04(b-1)</cite>;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Any felony in the commission of which a motor vehicle is used; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>Any offense committed in another state which, if committed in the District of Columbia, would constitute one of the offenses listed in paragraphs (1) through (7) of this subsection.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding subsection (a) of this section, the DMV shall not suspend registrations as described in subsection (a) of this section in cases where the conviction was based on:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A person's operation of a vehicle owned by or leased to the United States, the District of Columbia, another state, or a political subdivision thereof; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The person was acting as an agent of the United States, the District of Columbia, another state, or a political subdivision thereof.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Whenever a judgment of conviction for any offense listed in subsection (a) of this section has become final, the Superior Court of the District of Columbia shall transmit a record of the conviction to the DMV.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>A judgment of conviction shall be deemed to have become final for the purposes of this subsection if:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>No appeal is taken from the judgment upon the expiration of the time within which an appeal could have been taken; or</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>An appeal is taken from the judgment, the date upon which the judgment, having been sustained, can no longer be appealed from or reviewed on a writ of certiorari.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>If the DMV receives a record of a conviction of a nonresident, the DMV shall transmit the record to the state or territorial agency that issued the nonresident's license.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Nothing in this section shall limit the power of a judge of the Superior Court of the District of Columbia to limit or restrict a defendant's driving privileges as a condition of a pre-trial release or as a component of the defendant's sentence.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History" doc="Stat. 83-2-ch222" path="§37">May 25, 1954, 68 Stat. 130, ch. 222, § 37</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 85-792" type="History">Aug. 28, 1958, 72 Stat. 955, Pub. L. 85-792, § 9</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 86-730" type="History">Sept. 8, 1960, 74 Stat. 862, Pub. L. 86-730, § 5</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 4-29" type="History">Aug. 5, 1981, D.C. Law 4-29, § 604(b)(2), 28 DCR 3081</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 4-145" type="History">Sept. 14, 1982, D.C. Law 4-145, § 9, 29 DCR 3138</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 4-174" type="History">Mar. 9, 1983, D.C. Law 4-174, § 13, 29 DCR 5753</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 10-122" type="History">May 24, 1994, D.C. Law 10-122, § 5, 41 DCR 1658</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-212" type="History">Apr. 13, 1999, D.C. Law 12-212, § 3, 46 DCR 5</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-195" type="History">Mar. 2, 2007, D.C. Law 16-195, § 7, 53 DCR 8675</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-266" type="History">Apr. 27, 2013, D.C. Law 19-266, § 306, 59 DCR 12957</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-316" type="History">June 8, 2013, D.C. Law 19-316, § 4, 60 DCR 1713</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Section 8 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-316">D.C. Law 19-316</cite> provided that the act shall apply as of June 1, 2013.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 4 of the Reckless Driving Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-75, May 23, 2013,  60 DCR 7597, 20 DCSTAT 1428).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 306 of the Comprehensive Impaired Driving and Alcohol Testing Program Second Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-51, April 17, 2013,  60 DCR 6344, 20 DCSTAT 1360).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 306 of the Comprehensive Impaired Driving and Alcohol Testing Program Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-3, January 29, 2013,  60 DCR 2762, 20 DCSTAT 410).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary amendment of (a), see § 306 of the Comprehensive Impaired Driving and Alcohol Testing Program Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-508, October 26, 2012, 59 DCR 12774).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 7 of Anti-Drunk Driving Clarification Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2007 (D.C. Act 17-6, January 16, 2007,  54 DCR 1452).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 7 of Anti-Drunk Driving Clarification Second Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2006 (D.C. Act 16-518, October 27, 2006,  53 DCR 9104).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 4(d) of Anti-Drunk Driving Clarification Emergency Amendment Act of 2006 (D.C. Act 16-469, July 31, 2006,  53 DCR 6764).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 4 of the Driving Under the Influence Repeat Offenders Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2000 (D.C. Act 13-437, October 20, 2000,  47 DCR 8737).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90-day) repeal of expiration date of section, see § 4 of the Driving Under the Influence Repeat Offenders Emergency Amendment Act of 2000 (D.C. Act 13-382, July 24, 2000,  47 DCR 6697).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 4 of Driving Under the Influence Repeat Offenders Temporary Amendment Act of 2000 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 13-198">D.C. Law 13-198</cite>, October 21, 2000, law notification  47 DCR 8988).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 4 of Underage Drinking Temporary Amendment Act of 1993 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 10-12">D.C. Law 10-12</cite>, September 11, 1993, law notification  40 DCR 6834).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-316">D.C. Law 19-316</cite> substituted “aggravated reckless driving” for “reckless driving involving personal injury” in (a)(4).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-266">D.C. Law 19-266</cite> substituted “person is intoxicated as defined by <cite path="§50-2206.01|(9)">§ 50-2206.01(9)</cite>” for “person’s alcohol concentration is 0.08 grams or more either per 100 milliliters of blood or per 210 liters of breath or is 0.10 grams or more per 100 milliliters of urine” in (a).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 16-195">D.C. Law 16-195</cite>, in subsec. (a), substituted “person’s alcohol concentration is 0.08 grams or more either per 100 milliliters of blood or per 210 liters of breath or is 0.10 grams or more per 100 milliliters of urine” for “individual’s blood contains .08% or more, by weight, of alcohol, or while .38 micrograms or more of alcohol are contained in 1 milliliter of defendant’s breath, consisting substantially of alveolar air, or while defendant’s urine contains .10% or more, by weight, of alcohol”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 40-453.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 40-437.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Applicability" doc="D.C. Law 25-161" path="§3|(e)" codified:display="Note" app="2024-04-20" eff="2024-04-20">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 25-161" path="">D.C. Law 25-161</cite>: <cite doc="D.C. Law 25-161" path="§8">§ 8 of D.C. Law 25-161</cite> provided that the change made to this section by <cite doc="D.C. Law 25-161" path="§3|(e)">§ 3(e) of D.C. Law 25-161</cite> is subject to the inclusion of the law’s fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan. Therefore that amendment has not been implemented.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2024-04-20" doc="D.C. Law 25-161" eff="2024-04-20" path="§3|(e)" type="History"/>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Act 26-273" path="§2" type="Applicability" app="2026-03-04" eff="2026-03-04">Section 2 of <cite doc="D.C. Act 26-273" path="§2">D.C. Act 26-273</cite> provided that the amendments made to this section by <cite doc="D.C. Law 25-161" path="§3|(e)">section 3(e) of D.C. Law 25-161</cite> shall apply as of March 4, 2026.  Therefore those amendments have been implemented.
         </annotation>
    <annotation app="2026-03-04" doc="D.C. Act 26-273" eff="2026-03-04" path="§2" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
