<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>3-1471</num>
  <heading proof="needed">Establishment of Reparations Fund.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established as a special fund, the Reparations Fund, which shall be administered by the Chief Financial Officer of the District of Columbia in accordance with subsections (c) and (d) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The following funds shall be deposited into the Reparations Fund:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Funds appropriated by the District;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Gifts made to the Reparations Fund;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Grants made to the Reparations Fund; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Public and private donations made to the Reparations Fund.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The money in the Reparations Fund shall be used for the payment of reparations under the reparations program adopted by the District pursuant to the findings and recommendations of the Commission on Reparations established by <cite path="3|14D|I">subchapter I of this chapter</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The money deposited into the Reparations Fund but not expended in a fiscal year shall not revert to the unassigned fund balance of the General Fund of the District of Columbia at the end of a fiscal year, or at any other time.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Subject to authorization in an approved budget and financial plan, any funds appropriated in the Reparations Fund shall be continually available without regard to fiscal year limitation.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2025-03-07" doc="D.C. Law 25-264" eff="2025-03-07" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2025-03-07" doc="D.C. Law 25-264" eff="2025-03-07" path="ยง201" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
