<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>3-1461</num>
  <heading proof="needed">Commission on Reparations; establishment and purpose.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established a Commission on Reparations ("Commission").</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Commission shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>With a focus on African Americans and matters in the District of Columbia and the role of District government (in all its forms), study and analyze the:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Institution of slavery;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Transatlantic and domestic slave trade that existed in what is now the United States between the period of 1619 to 1865;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Federal and state governments support, constitutionally and statutorily, of the institution of slavery;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Lawful and de facto discrimination against enslaved people and other free African American people and their descendants from the end of the Civil War to the present, including economic, political, educational, and social discrimination, and structural and institutional racism;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>Direct benefits received by societal institutions, public and private, including higher education, corporate, religious, and associations as a result of the institution of slavery and its ongoing repercussions;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(F)</num>
        <text>Takings of property, generally, through civil asset forfeiture, the seizure of land acquired through eminent domain, and other unjust land seizures broadening the wealth gap, and, specifically, such takings by the District government or federal government between 1865 and 1973, including in the areas around Broad Branch Road, Chevy Chase, and Fort Reno, and in the southwest quadrant; which study may include soliciting public feedback from individuals who claim knowledge of property, familial or otherwise, that was taken by the District government or federal government;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(G)</num>
        <text>Compounding effect of the racial wealth gap over time and the impact of the racial wealth gap on areas such as health outcomes and public safety; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(H)</num>
        <text>Ongoing negative effects of the institution of slavery on African Americans living today and society at large in the United States today, including in such areas as the de facto segregation of the African American population, the criminal legal system, mass incarceration, prison conditions, police brutality, and education, displacement from the District, and other areas of continuing structural and institutional racism.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Based on the Commission's study and analysis of the matters described in paragraph (1) of this subsection and as further authorized by <cite path="3|14D|I">this subchapter</cite>, develop a proposal to provide eligible African Americans monetary reparations or other forms of redress.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The Commission shall be guided, but not restricted, by the 5 conditions for full reparations as detailed in principles 19 to 23 of the United Nations's General Assembly Resolution 60/147, including restitution, compensation, rehabilitation, satisfaction, and guarantees of non-repetition.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2025-03-07" doc="D.C. Law 25-264" eff="2025-03-07" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2025-03-07" doc="D.C. Law 25-264" eff="2025-03-07" path="ยง101" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
