<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>3-1466</num>
  <heading proof="needed">Meetings; quorum; sunset.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The first meeting of the Commission shall occur no later than June 1, 2025.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>At least 3 meetings shall be devoted to the issue of eligibility for reparations.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Commission shall consider holding a certain number of meetings during publicly accessible times, such as during weekends and in evenings.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Members shall remain in partnership throughout the life of the Commission with an organized coalition comprised of impacted African Americans and cross-sector leaders who have a demonstrated interest in reparations in the District of Columbia and who are based in the District of Columbia metropolitan area.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Five members of the Commission shall constitute a quorum.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The Commission shall sunset after December 31, 2027, or after the report required by <cite path="ยง3-1463|(a)|(1)">ยง 3-1463(a)(1)</cite> has been submitted; except, that nothing shall prohibit the Council from soliciting the assistance of former members of the Commission or the Executive Director during its review of the Commission's report or following the sunset. Following the sunset, the Commission members or Executive Director shall be entitled to per diem compensation and reimbursement of expenses for this assistance.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2025-03-07" doc="D.C. Law 25-264" eff="2025-03-07" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2025-03-07" doc="D.C. Law 25-264" eff="2025-03-07" path="ยง106" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
