<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>38-1834.02</num>
  <heading>Public Charter School Teacher Compensation for School Year 2025-2026.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>In School Year 2025-2026, the Office of the State Superintendent of Education shall make direct payments in a total amount of $30,785,832 from the Workforce Investments account to public charter LEAs to increase the compensation of public charter school educators.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>To receive funds authorized under subsection (a) of this section, a public charter LEA's chief executive officer or head of school shall sign an assurance that the funds provided under this section will be:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Used exclusively to increase the compensation of public charter school educators; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Paid to the public charter LEA's educators during School Year 2025-2026.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this section, the term:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>"Public charter LEA" means an individual public charter school or a group of public charter schools operating under a single charter.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>"Educator" means a school-based employee who directly supports students, including full-time and part-time teachers, teachers' aides, homebound teachers, hospital-based teachers, instructional coaches, athletic trainers, attendance coordinators, counselors, physical therapists, social workers, school psychologists, speech therapists, librarians, and classroom assistants of any type who assist in the instructional process, but excludes administrative personnel such as principals, assistant principals, deans, and office staff.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2023-09-06" doc="D.C. Law 25-50" eff="2023-09-06" path="IV" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 26-146" path="§4022" codified:display="Note" app="2025-12-06" eff="2025-09-03">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 26-146" path="§4022">§ 4022 of Fiscal Year 2026 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2025 (D.C. Act 26-146, Sept. 3, 2025, 72 DCR 9623)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2025-12-06" doc="D.C. Act 26-146" eff="2025-09-03" path="§4022" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 26-210" path="§4022" codified:display="Note" app="2025-12-06" eff="2025-11-24">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 26-210" path="§4022">§ 4022 of Fiscal Year 2026 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2025 (D.C. Act 26-210, Nov. 24, 2025, 72 DCR 13514)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2025-12-06" doc="D.C. Act 26-210" eff="2025-11-24" path="§4022" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2025-12-06" doc="D.C. Law 26-55" eff="2025-12-06" path="§4022" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
