<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>2-1515.05b</num>
  <heading proof="needed">Safe and supported pregnancy and delivery for detained youth.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Upon admission to a facility under its control and additionally when required as a baseline assessment for prescription of a recommended medication by a physician, the Department shall make a pregnancy test available to all youth who may become pregnant.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Upon confirmation of a detained youth's pregnancy, the Department shall advise the youth orally or in writing of the standards and policies governing pregnant youth in the Department's care.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Department shall ensure that pregnant youth in its care receive confidential, appropriate, timely, culturally responsive, and comprehensive healthcare, evaluation, and treatment from maternal healthcare providers licensed in the District, including:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Healthcare for conditions that emerge during pregnancy or postpartum, including contact with a maternal care provider within the first 3 weeks postpartum, followed by ongoing care as needed, and concluding with a comprehensive postpartum visit no later than 12 weeks after birth;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Specialized pregnancy or postpartum healthcare, if necessary, which may be referred to external healthcare providers, in accordance with <cite path="24|2|VIII-A">subchapter VIII-A of Chapter 2 of Title 24</cite>;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Counseling regarding:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Family planning;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Prenatal counseling and education;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Birth control;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Test results; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>Perinatal mental health conditions[; and]</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Medical, healthcare, and personal care supplies prescribed or recommended by a licensed healthcare provider treating a pregnant youth or reasonably requested by a pregnant youth, which shall be provided at no cost to the pregnant youth, including:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Equipment and cleaning supplies necessary to safely pump, store, and transport breast milk, including nursing brassieres, breast pumps, breast milk storage bags, detergent, bottle brushes, drying racks, a refrigerator of sufficient capacity, and a cooler; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The diet that is required by Department policy or is medically recommended during pregnancy and postpartum.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-335" type="History" path="§105b">Apr. 12, 2005, D.C. Law 15-335, § 105b</annotation>
    <annotation app="2026-06-11" doc="D.C. Law 26-130" eff="2026-06-11" path="§2" prefix="as added" target-path="2|15|I-A|A" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
