<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>10-1605.04</num>
  <text>
      *NOTE: This section was created by emergency legislation that will expire on December 24, 2025.*
      </text>
  <heading proof="needed">Local hiring, equity, and subcontracting requirements.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Sections 2, 4(a), (b), (c), (e)(1), (1C), (2), (3), (4), and (5), and 4a of the First Source Employment Agreement Act of 1984, effective June 29, 1984 (D.C. Law 5-93; D.C. Official Code §§ 2-219.01, 2-219.03(a), (b), (c), (e)(1), (1C), (2), (3), (4), and (5), and 2-219.03a), shall apply to the construction obligations of the Stadium Project and the Commercial Development (collectively "the Project"); provided, that good faith efforts will be required to ensure that 51% of all new hires for the Project are District residents; provided further, that residents of Wards 7 and 8 receive a hiring preference for at least 20% of the new jobs created in connection with the Project.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text><cite path="§32-1431">§ 32-1431</cite>, shall apply to the construction obligations of the Project; except, that 10%, with a goal of 35%, of all apprenticeship hours performed pursuant to apprenticeship programs required by <cite path="§32-1431|(a)">§ 32-1431(a)</cite> shall be performed by District residents and the Department of Employment Services may only impose fines for a failure to achieve the 10% requirement.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Small and Certified Business Enterprise Development and Assistance Act of 2005, effective October 20, 2005 (D.C. Law 16-33; D.C. Official Code § 2-218.01 <em>et seq.</em>), shall apply to the construction obligations of the Project, including professional services rendered in furtherance of the Project; except, that:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Developer shall require at least 20% equity, excluding debt financing, mezzanine financing, or other equity contributions by limited or institutional investors, and 20% development participation from certified business enterprises; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Forty percent, with a goal of 50%, of the adjusted development budget, as defined in the CBE Agreement referenced in section 6(a), shall be subcontracted to small business enterprises, with a preference for at least 10% of the small business enterprises to be located in, by order of priority, Wards 7, 8, 5, and 6; or, if there are insufficient qualified small business enterprises to completely fulfill the 40% requirement or the 50% goal, then the subcontracting requirement or goal may be satisfied by subcontracting the 40% requirement or 50% goal of the adjusted development budget to any qualified certified business enterprises, with a preference for at least 10% of the certified business enterprises located in, by order of priority, Wards 7, 8, 5, and 6; provided, that all reasonable efforts shall be made to ensure that qualified small business enterprises are significant participants in the overall subcontracting work.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <codify:annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Code" path="§10-1604.14" expire="2025-09-25" codified:display="Note">For temporary (90 days) creation of § 10-1605.04, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 26-150" path="§5">§ 5 of Robert F. Kennedy Campus Redevelopment Emergency Amendment Act of 2025 (D.C. Act 26-150, Sept. 25, 2025, 0 DCR 0)</cite>.</codify:annotation>
  <codify:annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Code" path="§10-1605.04" applicability="2025-09-25" delay="50" codified:display="Note" codified:doc="D.C. Code" codified:path="§10-1605.04">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 26-150" path="§5">§ 5 of Robert F. Kennedy Campus Redevelopment Emergency Amendment Act of 2025 (D.C. Act 26-150, Sept. 25, 2025, 0 DCR 0)</cite>.</codify:annotation>
  <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="§10-1605.04" before="heading" history="false" display-template="" codified:doc="D.C. Code" codified:path="§10-1605.04">
    <text>
      *NOTE: This section was created by emergency legislation that will expire on December 24, 2025.*
      </text>
  </codify:insert>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2025-09-03" doc="D.C. Act 26-146" eff="2025-09-03" path="II" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2025-09-25" doc="D.C. Act 26-150" eff="2025-09-25" path="" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2025-09-25" doc="D.C. Act 26-150" eff="2025-09-25" path="§5" type="History" display="false"/>
    <annotation app="2025-09-25" doc="D.C. Act 26-150" eff="2025-09-25" path="§5" type="History"/>
    <annotation history="false" type="Emergency Legislation" doc="D.C. Act 26-150" path="§5" codified:display="Note" app="2025-09-25" eff="2025-09-25">For temporary (90 days) creation of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 26-150" path="§5">§ 5 of Robert F. Kennedy Campus Redevelopment Emergency Amendment Act of 2025 (D.C. Act 26-150, Sept. 25, 2025, 0 DCR 0)</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
