<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>6-1415</num>
  <heading proof="needed">Single staircase multifamily residential buildings.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>No later than July 1, 2027, the Department of Buildings shall promulgate rules amending the Construction Codes to allow for a single entrance and egress stairway to serve multifamily residential buildings up to 6 stories above grade plane or high-rise buildings.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>For purposes of paragraph (1) of this subsection, the term "high-rise building" means a building with an occupied floor located more than 75 feet above the lowest level of fire-department vehicle access.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>In drafting rules required pursuant to subsection (a)(1) of this section, the Department shall consider:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Requirements that prevent the spread of fires and smoke in such multifamily residential buildings, including requiring the use of fire-resistive construction, and requiring the provision of adequate automatic fire sprinklers throughout a building;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Requirements that enable occupants to safely and quickly exit such a multifamily residential building in emergency situations, including establishing a maximum travel distance from the exit or entry door of any dwelling unit to the exit stairway and prohibiting dwelling unit doors from opening in the direction of an interior exit stairway;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Requirements limiting such multifamily residential buildings to either no more than 4 units per floor or a commensurate limitation on square footage per floor; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Any best practices in state, local, and international laws and codes that allow for the construction of multifamily residential buildings with a single entrance and egress stairway.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The considerations set forth in subsection (b) of this section shall not be construed to limit the Department's authority to promulgate or amend rules regarding multifamily residential buildings after satisfying the requirements set forth in subsection (a) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 6-216" type="History" path="§10f">Mar. 21, 1987, D.C. Law 6-216, § 10f</annotation>
    <annotation app="2026-07-18" doc="D.C. Law 26-152" eff="2026-07-18" path="§2|(b)" prefix="as added" target-path="6|14|I" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
