<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>1-301.193</num>
  <heading proof="needed">Transit corridor safety and emergency response program.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>No later than 180 days after [when applicable], the Deputy Mayor for Public Safety and Justice ("Deputy Mayor"), in consultation with the District Department of Transportation ("DDOT"), Metropolitan Police Department ("MPD"), and the Metro Transit Police Department ("MTPD"), shall establish a 2-year demonstration program of emergency communication and video surveillance systems at or near bus stops, train stations, or other public spaces to increase safety along transit routes in the District.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The emergency communication and video surveillance systems shall promptly connect an individual to emergency response services, and audio and video captured by the emergency communication and video surveillance systems may be used to identify violators of District criminal law.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The audio and video captured by the emergency communication and video surveillance systems shall be deleted after 30 calendar days, unless the footage relates to a violation of criminal law, in which case it shall be retained consistent with MPD's retention policies for body-worn camera footage.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The audio and video captured by the emergency communication and video surveillance systems shall not be subject to <cite path="2|5|II">subchapter II of Chapter 5 of Title 2</cite>, and shall not be released publicly, except as needed for use as evidence in criminal proceedings. Upon public release, the Mayor shall ensure the privacy of those identified in the footage through protective measures, including the blurring of faces of individuals who were not involved in incidents related to the criminal proceedings.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>As part of the implementation of the demonstration program, the Deputy Mayor shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Evaluate various emergency communication and video surveillance station configurations to identify the most appropriate device for use in the District;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Select locations for placement of emergency communication and video surveillance systems in consultation with MPD, MTPD, and DDOT; provided, that:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Priority shall be given to locations with a higher incidence of:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>Late-night or early morning ridership; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>Harassment, theft, or violent offenses; and</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>At least one emergency communication and video surveillance system shall be installed in each ward;</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Provide a report to the Council describing how the location for each emergency communication and video surveillance system was selected;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Install signs providing notice, in the 5 most commonly spoken languages in the District, at locations where an emergency communication and video surveillance system is installed, informing members of the public that audio and video footage is being recorded; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Collect appropriate data on the effectiveness of the emergency communication and video surveillance system, including how often the emergency communication stations were activated, whether audio or video information captured from the systems led to the successful identification of perpetrators of criminal offenses, and whether incidents of criminal offenses decreased at or near the emergency communication and video surveillance system locations following the installation of the emergency communication and video surveillance system.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>No later than 60 days after the conclusion of the 2-year demonstration program required by subsection (a) of this section, DDOT shall submit a report on the results of the demonstration program to the Council. The report shall include:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The locations, date, and timestamps for when the emergency communication  stations were used;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The total number of arrests made due to the conduct recorded or otherwise identified by the emergency communication and video surveillance systems; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The expenses incurred by the District to implement the demonstration program.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The Deputy Mayor shall provide for routine maintenance and repair of emergency communication stations and video surveillance technology in accordance with recommendations from the manufacturers.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>An operator of an emergency communication and video surveillance system shall have completed training in the procedures for the installation, testing, and operation of the device.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>The demonstration program shall use video technology that has the capacity to record images at a minimum of 15 frames per second or equivalent recording speed and at a resolution sufficient to clearly identify persons, objects, and locations monitored by the camera.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(h)</num>
    <text>Within 6 months after [when applicable], the Deputy Mayor, in consultation with DDOT, MPD, and MTPD, shall initiate a study on the prevalence of violence and crime that occurs at bus stops, train stations, and other public spaces in the District and identify and evaluate short-term and long-term strategies for reducing crime in those locations. Within one year after [when applicable], the Deputy Mayor shall provide to the Council a report on the study, including recommendations on the feasibility, efficacy, and environmental impact of the identified violence-reducing strategies and a cost-benefit analysis of identified strategies that includes a detailed cost breakdown for implementing each recommended strategy across the financial plan.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(i)</num>
    <text>No later than 180 days after [when applicable], the Mayor, pursuant to <cite path="2|5|I">subchapter I of Chapter 5 of Title 2</cite>, shall issue rules to implement the provisions of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(j)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this section, the term:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>"Bus stop" means any stop, either permanent or temporary, that is part of the Metrobus, DC Circulator, or Streetcar lines within the bounds of the District.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>"Emergency communication and video surveillance system" means an emergency communication station affixed with or in close proximity to continuous video surveillance technology operated by, or accessible to, the Metropolitan Police Department.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>"Emergency communication station" means a fixed station, illuminated by a bright blue or other colored light beacon, that features an alarm button that, when pressed, communicates directly with  an Office of Unified Communications emergency call center.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>"Operator of an emergency communication and video surveillance system" means a person authorized to set up, test, or operate an emergency communication and video surveillance system.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-21" type="History" path="ยง3024">Sept. 14, 2011, D.C. Law 19-21, ยง 3024</annotation>
    <annotation app="2024-05-01" doc="D.C. Act 25-411" eff="2024-05-01" path="ยง2|(b)" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
