<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>42-3404.03a</num>
  <heading proof="needed">Notice of transfer.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>If an opportunity to purchase is not provided pursuant to <cite path="§42-3404.02">§ 42-3404.02</cite>, the owner shall provide the Mayor written notice of a transfer of an interest ("Notice of Transfer") in a housing accommodation or of any ownership interest in a corporation, partnership, limited liability company, association, entity formed under <cite path="29|12">Chapter 12 of Title 29</cite>, or similar statutory provision of another jurisdiction, or other entity which owns a housing accommodation.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Tenants shall have 45 days after the date of receipt of the Notice of Transfer to file a petition for relief pursuant to §§ <cite path="§42-3405.03">42-3405.03</cite> or <cite path="§42-3405.03a">42-3405.03a</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>For a transfer that is not a sale pursuant to <cite path="§42-3404.02b|(b)">§ 42-3404.02b(b)</cite>, but for which a Notice of Transfer is required, the owner shall also provide copies of the Notice of Transfer to each tenant by certified mail or a delivery service providing delivery tracking confirmation. Notice to tenants shall be sent to their address at the housing accommodation unless a tenant has provided the owner with a different address in writing.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The Notice of Transfer shall be substantially in the form prescribed by the Mayor and shall provide at a minimum:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A statement of the rights of the tenant or the tenant organization under <cite path="42|34">this chapter</cite>;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>An accurate description of the transfer, including whether the transfer will result in any changes in management, current rents, or any applicable affordability requirements for the housing accommodation;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The date of the proposed transfer; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The reason, if any, why the owner asserts the transfer may not constitute a sale as defined in <cite path="§42-3404.02b">§ 42-3404.02b</cite>.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>In addition to any other requirements for the form of the Notice of Transfer prescribed by this section, a Notice of Transfer for a housing accommodation to be transferred for the purposes of receiving tax benefits pursuant to 26 U.S.C. § 42, or a comparable District program, shall include a description of the applicable federal or District subsidy, and a description of the steps in the transaction employed by the developer to avail itself of the subsidy.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>The owner's failure to provide the Notice of Transfer, or the provision of a notice that is fraudulent or contains material misrepresentations, shall create a rebuttable presumption that the transfer constitutes a sale for purposes of <cite path="42|34|IV">this subchapter</cite> and <cite path="42|34|V">subchapter V of this chapter</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>A tenant or tenant organization shall be precluded from asserting any rights under <cite path="42|34|IV">this subchapter</cite> and <cite path="42|34|V">subchapter V of this chapter</cite> for a transfer exempt under <cite path="§42-3404.02b|(b)">§ 42-3404.02b(b)</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(h)</num>
    <text>Any change in the transfer agreement that would invalidate a claim of exemption shall be reported in writing to the Mayor, substantially in a form prescribed by the Mayor, and proper notice shall be provided to the tenant or tenant organization.".</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 3-86" type="History" path="§403a">Sept. 10, 1980, D.C. Law 3-86, § 403a</annotation>
    <annotation app="2025-12-31" doc="D.C. Law 26-80" eff="2025-12-31" path="§301|(e)" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
