<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>42-3404.03b</num>
  <heading proof="needed">Cooling-off period; interference prohibited.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Within the first 5 business days following receipt of the offer of sale by the Mayor pursuant to <cite path="§42-3404.03">§ 42-3404.03</cite>, the Mayor shall provide all tenant support providers established under <cite path="§42-3404.02c">§ 42-3404.02c</cite> and qualified purchasers with a copy of the offer of sale.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A tenant organization of a housing accommodation with 5 or more units may not assign its purchase rights to a third party pursuant to <cite path="§42-3404.06">§ 42-3404.06</cite> prior to receiving a valid offer of sale or during the first 45 days following receipt of a valid offer of sale unless the tenant organization has submitted the following materials to the Department before receiving the offer of sale:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The tenant organization's registration application materials, including:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The name, address, and phone number of tenant officers and legal counsel (if any);</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>A copy of the articles of incorporation;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>A copy of the bylaws; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Documentation that the organization represents at least a majority of the occupied rental units at the time of registration; and</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Proof of certification that the tenant organization has received training on its rights under <cite path="42|34|IV">this subchapter</cite> from an organization or agency approved by the Department or by the Office of the Tenant Advocate, which shall be transmitted to the Department by the training organization or agency directly and include:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The date and time of the training;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The number of units represented at the training session; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>A statement affirming that a quorum was met under the tenant organization's bylaws.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>For housing accommodations with 2 through 4 units, other than 2-unit single family accommodations, covered by <cite path="§42-3404.10">§ 42-3404.10</cite>, a tenant, either jointly or individually, may not assign their purchase rights to a third party pursuant to <cite path="§42-3404.06">§ 42-3404.06</cite> prior to receiving a valid offer for sale or during the first 22 days following the receipt of a valid offer of sale, unless the tenant has received training from an organization or agency approved by the Department or by the Office of the Tenant Advocate on their rights under <cite path="42|34|IV">this subchapter</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Any person that contacts a tenant organization or individual tenant related to an offer or negotiation subject to <cite path="42|34|IV">this subchapter</cite> shall disclose:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The names, residence, and business addresses of each person with direct, indirect, legal, or beneficial ownership of a governance or total distributional interest of the entity as provided for in <cite path="§29-102.01|(a)|(6)">§ 29-102.01(a)(6)</cite> and <cite path="§29-102.01|(a)|(7)">(7)</cite>; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Any financial connection to the property.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>Neither the owner nor the third-party purchaser or any other agent or party with a financial or other interest in the accommodation shall interfere with a tenant's exercise of their rights under <cite path="42|34|IV">this subchapter</cite>. Interference includes:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Attempting to organize the tenants in an effort to persuade the tenants to waive or exercise rights in any particular manner without fully disclosing the interested party's financial or other interest in the outcome; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Failing to disclose that tenants have a right to no-cost training on their rights under <cite path="42|34|IV">this subchapter</cite>, as well as the right to a consultation with a tenant support provider.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 3-86" type="History" path="§403b">Sept. 10, 1980, D.C. Law 3-86, § 403b</annotation>
    <annotation app="2025-12-31" doc="D.C. Law 26-80" eff="2025-12-31" path="§301|(e)" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
