<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>42-3404.06</num>
  <heading proof="needed">Exercise or assignment of rights; secondary assignment.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The tenant may exercise rights under <cite path="42|34|IV">this subchapter</cite> in conjunction with a third party or by assigning or selling those rights to any party, whether private or governmental. The exercise, assignment, or sale of tenant rights may be for any consideration which the tenant, in the tenant's sole discretion, finds acceptable. Such an exercise, assignment, or sale may occur at any time in the process set forth in <cite path="42|34|IV">this subchapter</cite>; provided, that the cooling-off period in <cite path="§42-3404.03b">§ 42-3404.03b</cite> has elapsed, and may be structured in any way the tenant, in the tenant's sole discretion, finds acceptable.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>If a tenant assigns or sells the tenant's rights under <cite path="42|34|IV">this subchapter</cite>, the recipient may only further reassign the rights to a private or nonprofit corporation or a partnership of which the assignee or buyer is an owner, managing member, or officer who can legally bind the entity.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>No consideration shall be allowed in exchange for a secondary assignment.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>A tenant who has assigned or sold rights under <cite path="42|34|IV">this subchapter</cite> for consideration is entitled to said consideration regardless of whether the tenant has vacated the housing accommodation prior to receipt.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 3-86" type="History" path="§406">Sept. 10, 1980, D.C. Law 3-86, § 406, 27 DCR 2975</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-31" type="History">Sept. 6, 1995, D.C. Law 11-31, § 3(l), 42 DCR 3239</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary amendment of section, see § 3(l) of the Rental Housing Conversion and Sale Act of 1980 Reenactment and Amendment Emergency Act of 1995 (D.C. Act 11-47, May 4, 1995,  42 DCR 2410) and § 3(l) of the Rental Housing Conversion and Sale Act of 1980 Reenactment and Amendment Congressional Recess Emergency Act of 1995 (D.C. Act 11-96, July 19, 1995,  42 DCR 3837).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary amendment of section, see § 3(l) of the Rental Housing Conversion and Sale Act of 1980 Reenactment and Amendment Emergency Act of 1994 (D.C. Act 10-285, July 8, 1994,  41 DCR 4904).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 3(l) of Rental Housing Conversion and Sale Act of 1980 Temporary Extension Amendment Act of 1994 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 10-176">D.C. Law 10-176</cite>, September 22, 1994, law notification  41 DCR 6076).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 45-1635.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in <cite path="§42-3404.12">§ 42-3404.12</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2025-12-31" doc="D.C. Law 26-80" eff="2025-12-31" path="§301|(i)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
