<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>42-3404.03</num>
  <heading>Offer of sale.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>An offer of sale shall include, at minimum:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The asking price and material terms of the sale;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A statement that the tenant has the right to purchase the accommodation under <cite path="42|34|IV">this subchapter</cite> and a notice that the tenants are entitled to no-cost technical assistance and training on their rights provided by a tenant support provider approved by the Mayor;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>A statement as to whether a contract with a third party exists for sale of the accommodation and that the owner shall make a copy available to the tenant within 7 days after receiving a request; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>A statement that the owner shall make available to the tenant a floor plan of the building and an itemized list of monthly operating expenses, utility consumption rates, and capital expenditures for each of the 2 preceding calendar years within 7 days after receiving a request. The statement shall also indicate that the owner shall, at the same time, make available the most recent rent roll, list of tenants, and list of vacant apartments. If the owner does not have a floor plan, the owner may meet the requirement to provide a floor plan by stating in writing to the tenant that the owner does not have a floor plan; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>The name and contact information of all tenant support providers certified by the Mayor pursuant to <cite path="§42-3404.02c">§ 42-3404.02c</cite> as of the date of issuance of the offer of sale; provided, that if no such organizations have been certified, the owner will be deemed in compliance with this paragraph.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The owner shall provide each tenant with a written copy of the offer of sale by certified mail, a delivery service providing delivery tracking confirmation, or hand delivery. Notice to tenants shall be sent to their address at the housing accommodation unless a tenant has supplied in writing to the owner a different address for notice.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>On the same date as copies of the offer of sale are sent to tenants, the owner shall provide the Mayor with a written copy of the offer of sale and a signed statement confirming that copies of the offer of sale were provided to each tenant. The offer of sale shall be sent to the Mayor by registered or certified mail, return receipt requested, by commercial overnight delivery service that maintains proof of delivery, by hand delivery, or by any other method designated by the Department. If the owner delivers the notification to the Mayor by hand delivery, the Owner shall obtain a date stamped copy demonstrating the Mayor's receipt.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>If the housing accommodation includes occupied units that are not the subject of a current or expired written lease or rental agreement, then on the same date as copies of the offer of sale are sent to tenants, the owner shall post at each building entrance, or unit entrance if the units do not have a common building entrance, a notice, in a form to be developed by the Mayor, that an offer is being mailed to tenants, as defined in <cite path="§42-3404.01a|(4)">§ 42-3404.01a(4)</cite>, and that residents who have a right to occupy the accommodation pursuant to an oral lease must notify the owner or a designated representative and provide a rent receipt or other proof of tenancy no more than 15 days after receipt of the offer of sale.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Amendment of section by Law 10-144: Section 2(j) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 10-144">D.C. Law 10-144</cite> purported to amend (4) of this section to read as follows: “The owner shall provide each tenant and the Mayor a written copy of the offer of sale by first class mail and post a copy of the offer of sale in a conspicuous place in common areas of the housing accommodation if it consists of more than 1 unit. An offer includes, at a minimum: ”(4) A statement that the owner shall make available to the tenant a floor plan of the building and an itemized list of monthly operating expenses, utility consumption rates, and capital expenditures for each of the 2 preceding calendar years within 7 days after receiving a request. The statement shall also indicate that the owner shall, at the same time, make available the most recent rent roll, list of tenants, and list of vacant apartments. If the new owner does not have a floor plan, the owner may meet the requirement to provide a floor plan by stating in writing to the tenant that the owner does not have a floor plan.”</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Reenactment of Law 3-86: See Historical and Statutory Notes following <cite path="§42-3401.01">§ 42-3401.01</cite>.</text>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 3-86" type="History" path="§403">Sept. 10, 1980, D.C. Law 3-86, § 403, 27 DCR 2975</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 5-38" type="History">Nov. 5, 1983, D.C. Law 5-38, § 2(i), 30 DCR 4866</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-31" type="History">Sept. 6, 1995, D.C. Law 11-31, § 3(j), 42 DCR 3239</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-234" type="History">Oct. 21, 2008, D.C. Law 17-234, § 2(a), 55 DCR 9014</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary amendment of section, see § 3(j) of the Rental Housing Conversion and Sale Act of 1980 Reenactment and Amendment Emergency Act of 1995 (D.C. Act 11-47, May 4, 1995,  42 DCR 2410) and § 3(j) of the Rental Housing Conversion and Sale Act of 1980 Reenactment and Amendment Congressional Recess Emergency Act of 1995 (D.C. Act 11-96, July 19, 1995,  42 DCR 3837).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary amendment of section, see § 3(j) of the Rental Housing Conversion and Sale Act of 1980 Reenactment and Amendment Emergency Act of 1994 (D.C. Act 10-285, July 8, 1994,  41 DCR 4904).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 3(j) of Rental Housing Conversion and Sale Act of 1980 Temporary Extension Amendment Act of 1994 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 10-176">D.C. Law 10-176</cite>, September 22, 1994, law notification  41 DCR 6076).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 17-234">D.C. Law 17-234</cite> rewrote the lead-in language, which had read as follows: “The owner shall provide each tenant and the Mayor a written copy of the offer of sale by first class mail and post a copy of the offer of sale in a conspicuous place in common areas of the housing accommodation if it consists of more than 1 unit. An offer includes, at a minimum:”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 45-1632.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in <cite path="§42-3404.32">§ 42-3404.32</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation app="2025-12-31" doc="D.C. Law 26-80" eff="2025-12-31" path="§301|(d)|(2)|(B)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2025-12-31" doc="D.C. Law 26-80" eff="2025-12-31" path="§301|(d)|(2)|(C)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2025-12-31" doc="D.C. Law 26-80" eff="2025-12-31" path="§301|(d)|(2)|(D)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2025-12-31" doc="D.C. Law 26-80" eff="2025-12-31" path="§301|(d)|(2)|(A)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2025-12-31" doc="D.C. Law 26-80" eff="2025-12-31" path="§301|(d)|(3)" type="History"/>
    <annotation app="2025-12-31" doc="D.C. Law 26-80" eff="2025-12-31" path="§301|(d)|(1)" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
