<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>5-1501.05a</num>
  <heading proof="needed">Chief Forensic Sciences Officer; appointment, qualifications, duties, and other personnel.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Mayor shall appoint, with the advice and consent of the Council in accordance with paragraph (2) of this subsection, a Chief Forensic Sciences Officer of the Laboratory. The Chief Forensic Sciences Officer shall report directly to the Director and may be removed only by the Mayor upon a written finding of good cause, subject to the right of appeal.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Mayor shall submit a nomination for Chief Forensic Sciences Officer to the Council for a 90-day period of review, excluding days of Council recess. If the Council does not approve or disapprove the nomination, by resolution, within the 90-day review period, the nomination shall be deemed disapproved.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>To be eligible for appointment, the Chief Forensic Sciences Officer shall have:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Graduated from an accredited college or university with a masters or doctoral degree in an applicable area of science or forensic analysis;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Demonstrated training and experience in scientific research and methodology;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Demonstrated management and administrative experience;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Demonstrated comprehensive knowledge of forensic sciences;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>A minimum of 10 years' experience being employed at a forensic sciences laboratory; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>A minimum of 5 years' experience directing or supervising both scientific and administrative staff in a forensic science laboratory setting.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Chief Forensic Sciences Officer shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Oversee the operations of all forensic science services in the Laboratory;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Ensure that all forensic science services in the Laboratory are in compliance with accreditation requirements and meet rigorous evidence-based practices;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Ensure that accreditation and evidence-based practices for all forensic science services in the Laboratory are maintained;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Address and rectify nonconformances for all forensic science services in the Laboratory;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Develop and promulgate training manuals and standard operating procedures, including:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Protocols for forensic testing, examination, and analysis;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Procedures for handling case-specific information to minimize bias;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Standards for the maintenance and calibration of all equipment and materials, including standards for maintaining logs documenting the maintenance and calibration performed;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Procedures for estimations of uncertainty;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>Procedures for monitoring the quality of forensic analysis;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(F)</num>
        <text>Procedures for regular internal and external audits;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(G)</num>
        <text>Proficiency testing protocols;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(H)</num>
        <text>Internal validation studies; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(I)</num>
        <text>Standards for reporting results, including model laboratory reports and guidelines for the presentation of results in court; and</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Address and implement any corrective action identified by the Board pursuant to section 13a(c)(1)(C).</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2023-04-21" doc="D.C. Law 24-348" eff="2023-04-21" path="ยง2|(h)" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
