<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>5-1501.03a</num>
  <heading proof="needed">Director; appointment, qualifications, compensation, and term.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Laboratory shall be headed by a Director who shall be appointed by the Mayor, with the advice and consent of the Council.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Mayor shall submit a nomination for the position of Director to the Council for a 90-day period of review, excluding days of Council recess. If the Council does not approve or disapprove the nomination, by resolution, within the 90-day review period, the nomination shall be deemed disapproved.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Director shall have demonstrated knowledge of forensic sciences and have:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Graduated from an accredited college or university with a master's degree or higher in an applicable area of science;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Demonstrated management and administrative skills in the public or private sector; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>A minimum of 5 years' management-level experience supervising employees in a government agency or private business association with more than 50 employees.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Director shall be compensated at a rate equal to Level 3 of the Public Safety Executive Service pay schedule pursuant to section 1052a of the District of Columbia Government Comprehensive Merit Personnel Act of 1978, effective May 2, 2015 (D.C. Law 20-267; D.C. Official Code ยง 1-610.52a).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Director shall be appointed for a 6-year term.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>If a vacancy in the position of Director occurs as a consequence of resignation, disability, death, or reason other than the expiration of the term of the Director, the Mayor shall appoint a replacement, subject to confirmation by the Council, to fill the unexpired term. A person appointed to fill the unexpired term shall serve only for the remainder of the term.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The Director shall not be subject to removal from office before expiration of the Director's term, except upon a written finding of the Mayor of good cause, subject to the right of appeal.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>No person shall serve as Director in a holdover capacity for longer than 180 days after the expiration of the term.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation app="2023-04-21" doc="D.C. Law 24-348" eff="2023-04-21" path="ยง2|(d)" prefix="as added" type="History"/>
  </annotations>
</section>
